<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Solar Energy on Timur Ergen</title>
    <link>https://tergen.org/tags/solar-energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solar Energy on Timur Ergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tergen.org/tags/solar-energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paper on expectation management in technology policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</guid>
      <description>This article builds on the literature on sociotechnical imaginaries and the sociology of expectations to engage in the discussion of how expectation alignment facilitates the development of novel technologies. While existing scholarship has elaborated on how expectations alignment is important to support technological development, it has not fully explored how the challenges of expectation alignment are translated into practices of expectation management and collective governance over the innovation process. Based on a range of archival sources, the article examines three historical episodes of photovoltaics development in locations that had spearheaded its development: the United States, Japan and Germany. Based on these historical episodes, the article suggests three core issues for the management of expectations in technological development: the creation, adaptation and materialization of shared imaginaries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on collective action and imagined futures</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</guid>
      <description>Der Aufsatz entwickelt eine neopragmatistische Theorie kollektiven Handelns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on innovation policy in a volume on Uncertain Futures</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2018_aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2018_aligned/</guid>
      <description>The paper compares technology policies for coal liquifaction and solar energy in the 1970s and 1980s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Große Hoffnungen und brüchige Koalitionen: Politik, Industrie und die schwierige Durchsetzung der Photovoltaik</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/book/book1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/book/book1/</guid>
      <description>The book reconstructs the history of policies to support solar photovoltaics across countries.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
