<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncertainty on Timur Ergen</title>
    <link>https://tergen.org/tags/uncertainty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncertainty on Timur Ergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tergen.org/tags/uncertainty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paper on energy crises</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_contested/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_contested/</guid>
      <description>The oil crisis of 1973/74 is commonly seen as the advent of state-led attempts to restructure rich societies&amp;#39; energy infrastructures. Indeed, from a historical perspective, crises have repeatedly facilitated infrastructural transformations toward sustainability. But under what conditions can crises challenge existing orders and promote alternative infrastructures? Drawing on a historical vignette that reconstructs the public discourse emerging around the first oil crisis in the United States, this article proposes to reconsider the transformative potential of crises from a perspective focusing on the contested constitution of the future. We argue that the potential of crises to foster broader processes of infrastructural change is dependent on the capacity of actors to discursively challenge hopes and expectations inscribed in established infrastructures. As the example of the first oil crisis illustrates, crises are instances in which political actors engage in interpretative struggles to settle on whether disruptions present &amp;#39;real&amp;#39; crises that require infrastructural transformation - or are mere accidents, errors, or irregularities that existent infrastructure can either withstand or requires only minor adaption as a result. In these discursive struggles, images of the future are contested on three layers: tangible experiences are linked to or detached from broader future consequences; potential causes are projected into the future or relegated to the past; and feasible future remedies are conceived or discarded. It is on these three layers of crisis discourse that the future is &amp;#39;opened up,&amp;#39; and alternative infrastructures become conceivable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on expectation management in technology policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</guid>
      <description>This article builds on the literature on sociotechnical imaginaries and the sociology of expectations to engage in the discussion of how expectation alignment facilitates the development of novel technologies. While existing scholarship has elaborated on how expectations alignment is important to support technological development, it has not fully explored how the challenges of expectation alignment are translated into practices of expectation management and collective governance over the innovation process. Based on a range of archival sources, the article examines three historical episodes of photovoltaics development in locations that had spearheaded its development: the United States, Japan and Germany. Based on these historical episodes, the article suggests three core issues for the management of expectations in technological development: the creation, adaptation and materialization of shared imaginaries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on expectations in the economy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_transcending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_transcending/</guid>
      <description>The chapter discusses sociological analyses of expectations in the economy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on collective action and imagined futures</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</guid>
      <description>Der Aufsatz entwickelt eine neopragmatistische Theorie kollektiven Handelns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on technological innovation and pragmatist thought</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_pragmatismus_innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_pragmatismus_innovation/</guid>
      <description>Der Aufsatz entwickelt eine neopragmatistische Theorie technologischer Innovation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
