<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Timur Ergen</title>
    <link>https://tergen.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Timur Ergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tergen.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of Institutional Theory (University of Bremen)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_inst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_inst/</guid>
      <description>This seminar introduces theories of institutions from across the social sciences, covering classical origins through recent debates about institutional change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism and Modern Society (University of Bremen)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_capital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_capital/</guid>
      <description>This seminar explores central topics of political economy and economic sociology, from the origins of capitalism to theories on the relationship between capitalism and democracy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinal Society (University of Bremen)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_ordinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/25ws_ordinal/</guid>
      <description>This seminar examines the effects of digital technologies on social orders, individuals and social inequalities, focusing on Marion Fourcade and Kieran Healy&amp;#39;s concept of &amp;#39;The Ordinal Society.&amp;#39;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Paper on Conditionality in Regulation and Governance</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2025-01-07-rg-conditionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2025-01-07-rg-conditionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en/staffmembers/fabio-bulfone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fabio Bulfone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://in.bgu.ac.il/humsos/soc-ant/en/pages/staff/emaggor-en.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Erez Maggor&lt;/a&gt; I have just published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/rego.70050&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper on conditionality in industrial policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on industrial policy conditionalities</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2025_conditionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2025_conditionality/</guid>
      <description>Conditionality was a central concern in the development literature of the 1990s. With the significant expansion of targeted public support to private firms since the Great Financial Crisis, the issue of conditionality has once again become a focal point in industrial policy debates. Despite the growing interest in the concept, the existing literature lacks a systematic conceptualization of conditionality within the context of industrial policy and does not outline the political factors that enable state actors to introduce it. This article addresses this gap by critically reviewing the existing literature and providing a systematic political economy of conditionality. We offer an overview of the literature on conditionality, examining different industries, historical periods, and national contexts. In doing so, we make three key contributions to the debate on industrial policy and regulatory instruments more broadly. First, we distinguish between two broad approaches to encoding conditionality in industrial policy: hard-coding and soft-coding. Next, we map the coalitional, institutional, ideational, and global contextual factors that facilitate conditionality. Finally, we present two vignettes of recent industrial policy initiatives in the European Union and the United States as illustrative cases. This conceptual exercise, intended to lay the foundation for future causal research on conditionality, demonstrates that the presence of conditionality is not merely a technical matter of political design but is instead shaped by configurations of political economy factors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Paper on the evolution of European climate policies in Regulation and Governance</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2025-01-03-rg-losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2025-01-03-rg-losers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/person/129459&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Luuk Schmitz&lt;/a&gt; I have just published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/rego.70004&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper on the evolution of European climate policies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/location/</guid>
      <description>Timur Ergen&amp;#39;s addresses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/officehours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/officehours/</guid>
      <description>Schedule and location for Timur Ergen&amp;#39;s office hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on the rise of managed decline in European climate policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2025_losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2025_losers/</guid>
      <description>Decarbonization forces societies to cope with the restructuring and outright unwinding of assets, firms, workers, industries, and regions. We argue that this problem has created legitimacy for industrial policies managing the reallocation of resources. We illustrate this dynamic by documenting incremental state-building in the European Union, an administration institutionally tilted toward regulatory statehood and the making of the Single Market in energy since the 1990s. European greening policies, we argue, have incrementally lessened the primacy of regulatory tools and have introduced a plethora of instruments to accelerate green restructuring and carbon unwinding. Best understood as a process of multi-sited institutional layering, the European Union increasingly appears to complement financial and regulatory instruments to effect green energy transitions with the management of decline in targeted regions and sectors, based on targeted funds and targeted transition planning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Applications: Villa Vigoni-Gespraech on Europe and the Geoeconomic Challenge</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-11-17-vigoni-ec-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-11-17-vigoni-ec-call/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lse.ac.uk/european-institute/people/di-carlo-donato&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donato Di Carlo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hertie-school.org/de/research/faculty-and-researchers/profile/person/hassel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anke Hassel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gufaculty360.georgetown.edu/s/contact/00336000014Rao3AAC/kathleen-mcnamara&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kate McNamara&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unibo.it/sitoweb/manuela.moschella/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manuela Moschella&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m organizing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.villavigoni.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Villa Vigoni-Gespräch&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lsquo;Europe and the Geoeconomic Challenge&amp;rsquo;, 22 to 24 April 2025, Loveno di Menaggio, Italy. We&amp;rsquo;re inviting applications for up to three advanced students and early career researchers to participate. The deadline for applications is 10 January 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detailed call for applications can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tergen.org/2025_cfa_vigoni_geoeconomic.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: Socio-economic Review Special Issue on »The Socio-economics of Loss and Decline in the Climate Crisis«</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-11-17-ser-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-11-17-ser-call/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://soc.univie.ac.at/ueber-uns/valentina-ausserladscheider/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Valentina Ausserladscheider&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/person/124306&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Philipp Golka&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m organizing a SASE mini-conference on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sase.org/event/2025-montreal/#mini&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Socio-economics of asset stranding&lt;/a&gt; in Montréal in July 2025. If you&amp;rsquo;re working on climate change mitigation and adaptation please consider joining us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detailed call can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tergen.org/2025_sase_mc_call.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Applications: SASE Early Career Workshop</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-17-11-cc-sase_ecw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-17-11-cc-sase_ecw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m chairing the 2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://sase.org/event/2025-montreal/#2025-sase-early-career-workshop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SASE Early Career Workshop&lt;/a&gt; committee. The SASE Early Career Workshop (ECW) is a one-day workshop that provides an opportunity for a longer and deeper discussion of applicants&amp;rsquo; conference papers. It takes place the day before the start of the annual conference (8 July 2025). The 2025 Early Career Workshop will be hosted in partnership with McGill University, with senior SASE and McGill professors. The (hard) deadline for submissions: 16 December 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vorlesung Soziologische Theorie (University of Oldenburg)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/24ws_soctheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/24ws_soctheory/</guid>
      <description>This lecture covers fundamental sociological concepts and selected theories of the social, covering both classical and contemporary perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soziologie der Klimapolitik (University of Oldenburg)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/24ws_verkauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/24ws_verkauf/</guid>
      <description>The seminar builds on the lecture in Sociological Theory, deepening central concepts and arguments through discussion of latest applications of sociological theory to the problem of climate change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: SASE Montreal Mini Conference on Climate Change Adaptation and Mitigation</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-17-10-cc-sase_mc_strand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-17-10-cc-sase_mc_strand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://soc.univie.ac.at/ueber-uns/valentina-ausserladscheider/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Valentina Ausserladscheider&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/person/124306&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Philipp Golka&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m organizing a SASE mini-conference on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sase.org/event/2025-montreal/#mini&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Socio-economics of asset stranding&lt;/a&gt; in Montréal in July 2025. If you&amp;rsquo;re working on climate change mitigation and adaptation please consider joining us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detailed call can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tergen.org/2025_sase_mc_call.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Paper on Industrial Policy Conditionalities</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-01-10-cc-conditionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-01-10-cc-conditionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en/staffmembers/fabio-bulfone#tab-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fabio Bulfone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bgu.ac.il/en/standarts/new-faculty-and-staff/erez-maggor/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Erez Maggor&lt;/a&gt; I have just published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://pure.mpg.de/rest/items/item_3612897_2/component/file_3612917/content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper on the politics of conditionality in industrial policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soziologische Forschungspraxis (University of Wuppertal)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/24ss_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/24ss_model/</guid>
      <description>This seminar provides practical skills and reflective knowledge useful for conducting independent social science research projects, combining findings from interdisciplinary science studies with the philosophy and sociology of science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vorlesung Organisationssoziologie (University of Wuppertal)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/24ss_orgasoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/24ss_orgasoc/</guid>
      <description>This lecture introduces fundamental theories and concepts in organizational sociology, covering rationalization, bureaucracy, and various theoretical approaches to understanding organizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SER-Review Symposium on Lehdonvirta&#39;s Cloud Empires</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2024-01-05-cc-ser_ce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2024-01-05-cc-ser_ce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/ser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Socio-Economic Review&lt;/a&gt; has published our &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/ser/mwae023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;review symposium&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oii.ox.ac.uk/people/profiles/vili-lehdonvirta/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vili Lehdonvirta&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudempires.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cloud Empires: How digital platforms are overtaking the state and how we can regain control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Applications: Sociology of Markets Seminar in Paris</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2023-10-04-cc-cfa_socmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2023-10-04-cc-cfa_socmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have put out a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tergen.org/teaching/teaching_files/cfa_sociology_of_markets_2024.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;call for applications&lt;/a&gt; for a PhD seminar on the sociology of markets. The seminar is fully funded by the DFH/UFA and will be held at Sciences Po Paris from January 10–12, 2024. Please apply by &lt;strong&gt;October 31st&lt;/strong&gt; and join us to discuss the future of the sociology of markets with an interdisciplinary group of researchers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on business power and the revival of industrial policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_strings/</guid>
      <description>This paper contributes to Comparative Political Economy (CPE) by developing an analytical concept of corporate welfare. Corporate welfare—the transfer of public funds and benefits to corporate actors with weak or no conditionality—is a prominent form of state-business relations that CPE scholarship regularly overlooks and misinterprets. Such transfers should be understood as a structural privilege of business in a globalized post-Fordist capitalism, and an increasingly common strategy through which states attempt to steward national economic dynamism within a highly constrained range of policy options. However, without a well-developed concept of corporate welfare—premised upon the key criterion of conditionality—studies that identify a &amp;#39;return&amp;#39; of the state in industrial planning misrepresent these transfers to business as a reassertion of state influence and control, rather than a reflection of state weakness and subordination. The paper provides the analytical building blocks to properly conceptualize transfers to business, works out the core challenges for empirical research, and provides empirical illustrations of this burgeoning phenomenon from the fields of unconventional monetary policy, privatization, and urban political economy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on imaginaries in economic policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_silicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_silicon/</guid>
      <description>How do policy paradigms change? This article demonstrates that changing social imaginaries about economic growth enabled paradigmatic changes in USA corporate tax policy in the 1980s. Based on archival sources, it reconstructs how policy makers switched from focused support for capital-intensive smoke-stack industries towards support for emerging high tech-sectors between two major tax-bills in 1981 and 1986. This switch was made possible by the emergence of what we call the Silicon Valley imaginary—the idea that sound economic policies stimulate the reallocation of society’s resources towards new economic fields. The emergence of this social imaginary resulted from political realignments and changing notions of economic growth and justice. The search for sources of future economic growth and societal coalitions led policy-makers to appropriate ideas about the promises of new industries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication on Crisis Perceptions in Historical Social Research</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2023-01-10-cc-hrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2023-01-10-cc-hrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/27182682&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesis.org/en/hsr/current-issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Historical Social Research&lt;/a&gt; on sense-making during the First Oil Crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sociology of Markets (MPIfG/Sciences Po)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/23ws_socmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/23ws_socmark/</guid>
      <description>This intensive course provides analytical and conceptual tools to study markets from a sociological perspective, examining how markets are institutions interwoven with political, social, and cultural structures. Beyond covering the basics, the seminar explores recently vibrant research frontiers to discuss with students the future of the field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on comparative methodology and corporate globalization</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_firm_foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2023_firm_foundations/</guid>
      <description>The discipline of comparative political economy (CPE) relies heavily on aggregate, country-level economic indicators. However, the practices of multinational corporations have increasingly undermined this approach to measurement. The problem of indicator drift is well documented by a growing critical literature and calls for systematic methodological attention in CPE. We present the case for a rocky but ultimately rewarding middle road between indicator fatalism and indicator faith. We illustrate our argument by examining two important cases—Sweden’s recent export success and the financialization of non-financial corporations in France. A careful parsing of the data suggests corrections to common characterizations of the two cases. Swedish exports have been reshaped by intragroup trade among foreign subsidiaries of domestic corporations. The growth of financial assets held by French firms is attributable to the growth of foreign direct investment and to cumulative revaluation effects, while what remains of financialization is concentrated among the very largest firms. Based on these findings, we propose a methodological routine that parses data by zooming in on the qualitative specifics of countries, sectors, and firms, while using all available options for disaggregation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on rival views of competition</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_rival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_rival/</guid>
      <description>Competition is a constitutive feature of capitalist societies. Social conflicts over the introduction, abolition and regulation of market organization are saturated with implicit moral arguments concerning the desirability of competition. Yet, unlike private property, exchange relations and social inequalities, economic competition has rarely been the explicit core of moral debates over capitalism. Drawing on a broad variety of social science literature, this article reconstructs, maps and systematizes ethical arguments about economic competition in capitalist societies. We discuss six contradictory rival views of economic competition and illustrate their influence by providing historical examples of the respective views in action in political-economic debates. This article serves as a mapping groundwork for reviving the systematic ethical debate on economic competition. In addition, our map of rival views lends itself to use as a structuring tool in empirical research on the moral economy and ideational embeddedness of capitalist societies, markets and firms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication on Globalization and Comparative Analysis in Competition &amp; Change</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2022-05-15-cc-firmfound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2022-05-15-cc-firmfound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/10245294221093704&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/home/cch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Competition &amp;amp; Change&lt;/a&gt; on the problems economic globalization creates for comparative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication on Industrial Policy in Competition &amp; Change</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2022-05-15-cc_nostrings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2022-05-15-cc_nostrings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/10245294221101145&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;journals.sagepub.com/home/cch&#34;&gt;Competition &amp;amp; Change&lt;/a&gt; on the decline of conditionality in state aid to business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on energy crises</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_contested/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2022_contested/</guid>
      <description>The oil crisis of 1973/74 is commonly seen as the advent of state-led attempts to restructure rich societies&amp;#39; energy infrastructures. Indeed, from a historical perspective, crises have repeatedly facilitated infrastructural transformations toward sustainability. But under what conditions can crises challenge existing orders and promote alternative infrastructures? Drawing on a historical vignette that reconstructs the public discourse emerging around the first oil crisis in the United States, this article proposes to reconsider the transformative potential of crises from a perspective focusing on the contested constitution of the future. We argue that the potential of crises to foster broader processes of infrastructural change is dependent on the capacity of actors to discursively challenge hopes and expectations inscribed in established infrastructures. As the example of the first oil crisis illustrates, crises are instances in which political actors engage in interpretative struggles to settle on whether disruptions present &amp;#39;real&amp;#39; crises that require infrastructural transformation - or are mere accidents, errors, or irregularities that existent infrastructure can either withstand or requires only minor adaption as a result. In these discursive struggles, images of the future are contested on three layers: tangible experiences are linked to or detached from broader future consequences; potential causes are projected into the future or relegated to the past; and feasible future remedies are conceived or discarded. It is on these three layers of crisis discourse that the future is &amp;#39;opened up,&amp;#39; and alternative infrastructures become conceivable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in the MPIfG Discussion Paper Series</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-12-15-dp-firmfound/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-12-15-dp-firmfound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/pu/dp_abstracts/dp21-5.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Max Planck Institute&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Discussion Paper Series on the problems economic globalization creates for comparative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gesellschaftlicher Wandel und Grüne Energie (University of Wuppertal)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/21ws_green/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/21ws_green/</guid>
      <description>This seminar introduces research on the transformation of energy systems, examining the political, social, and economic dynamics of sustainable energy transitions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in the Socio-economic Review</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-10-19-ser_silicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-10-19-ser_silicon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/ser/mwab051&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;em&gt;Socio-economic Review&lt;/em&gt; on the history of American tax policies in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on expectation management in technology policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_shifting/</guid>
      <description>This article builds on the literature on sociotechnical imaginaries and the sociology of expectations to engage in the discussion of how expectation alignment facilitates the development of novel technologies. While existing scholarship has elaborated on how expectations alignment is important to support technological development, it has not fully explored how the challenges of expectation alignment are translated into practices of expectation management and collective governance over the innovation process. Based on a range of archival sources, the article examines three historical episodes of photovoltaics development in locations that had spearheaded its development: the United States, Japan and Germany. Based on these historical episodes, the article suggests three core issues for the management of expectations in technological development: the creation, adaptation and materialization of shared imaginaries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on expectations in the economy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_transcending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_transcending/</guid>
      <description>The chapter discusses sociological analyses of expectations in the economy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on small firm ideologies</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_mittelstand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_mittelstand/</guid>
      <description>Corporate concentration is currently being discussed as a core reason for the crisis of democratic capitalism. It is seen as a prime mover for wage stagnation and alienation, economic inequalities and discontent with democracy. A tacit coalition of progressive anti-monopoly critiques and small business promoters considers more deconcentrated corporate structures to be a panacea for the crisis of democratic capitalism, arguing that small firms in competition are better for employment, equality and democracy. This paper offers a brief outline of ideas of the anti-monopoly and small business ideal and critically evaluates whether a more deconcentrated economy may live up to these promises. While we agree that the plea for strengthened antitrust enforcement contains relevant and promising prospects for reform, our analysis concludes on a decidedly critical note. In particular, we caution against romanticized notions of the small capitalist firm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in Energy Research and Social Science</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-06-25-solar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-06-25-solar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S221462962100270X&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Energy Research and Social Science&lt;/em&gt; on the history of solar energy policies in Germany, Japan and the United States with M. Umemura.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in Symposium on Piketty&#39;s Capitalism and Ideology</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-06-25-mittelstand/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-06-25-mittelstand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.analyse-und-kritik.net/HeftDetails.php?AusgabeID=84&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Analyse &amp;amp; Kritik&lt;/em&gt; on the history and limits of the Mittelstand-ideal in debates about democratic capitalism with S. Kohl.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on collective action and imagined futures</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_kollektive_erwartung/</guid>
      <description>Der Aufsatz entwickelt eine neopragmatistische Theorie kollektiven Handelns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on technological innovation and pragmatist thought</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_pragmatismus_innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2021_pragmatismus_innovation/</guid>
      <description>Der Aufsatz entwickelt eine neopragmatistische Theorie technologischer Innovation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter in volume on economic nationalism</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-05-24-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-05-24-nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed a chapter to &lt;a href=&#34;https://homepage.uni-graz.at/de/klaus.kraemer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Klaus Kraemer&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kuwi.europa-uni.de/de/lehrstuhl/vs/sozwi/team/muennich/muennich/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sascha Münnich&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.campus.de/buecher-campus-verlag/wissenschaft/soziologie/oekonomischer_nationalismus-15602.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;edited volume on the sociology of economic nationalism&lt;/a&gt;. My chapter investigates the EU&amp;rsquo;s trade policy response to overcapacity in the solar industry as a moral economic conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter in Handbook of Economic Sociology for the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-04-07-econsochandbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-04-07-econsochandbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/people/jb1/index_en.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jens Beckert&lt;/a&gt; we contributed a chapter to a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783030616182&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Handbook of Economic Sociology for the 21st Century&lt;/a&gt;, edited by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uni-trier.de/universitaet/fachbereiche-faecher/fachbereich-iv/faecher/soziologie/professuren/wirtschaftssoziologie/team/prof-dr-andrea-maurer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Andrea Maurer&lt;/a&gt;. The hardcover version has just arrived, so the ebook should be available soon. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://pure.mpg.de/rest/items/item_3214547_2/component/file_3214663/content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt; of our chapter has been published as an MPIfG discussion paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two papers in edited volume on pragmatism in the social sciences</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-04-01-pragmatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-04-01-pragmatism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007%2F978-3-662-62172-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;new edited volume&lt;/a&gt; on pragmatist social science features two of my papers. A first one with the title &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-662-62172-1_12&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eine pragmatistische Theorie technologischer Innovation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; explores how to think about technological innovation from a Deweyan perspective. The second, co-authored with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wiso.uni-hamburg.de/fachbereich-sowi/professuren/beyer/team/seeliger-martin.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Seeliger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-662-62172-1_13&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kollektive Erwartungsbildung und die Entstehung von Kooperation&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates how recent thinking about imagined futures can be the basis of a pragmatist understanding of collective action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essay on the First Oil Crisis</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-03-25-econsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-03-25-econsoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/forschung/wissdetails_de.asp?MitarbID=757&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lisa Suckert&lt;/a&gt; and I published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://econsoc.mpifg.de/43430/04_Ergen_Suckert-NL_22-2_March2021.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;short essay on the making of the First Oil Crisis&lt;/a&gt; in the Economic Sociology Newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essay on small firm ideologies on Makronom</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2021-03-20-makronom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2021-03-20-makronom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Kohl and I published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://makronom.de/der-mittelstand-als-retter-des-demokratischen-kapitalismus-38483&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;short essay on small firm ideologies&lt;/a&gt; on Makronom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for contributions – The Role of the State in Digital Transitions</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2020-12-21-sasedig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2020-12-21-sasedig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tergen.org/2021_sase_digital.pdf&#34;&gt;Call for contributions&lt;/a&gt; for a panel series on the state in digital transitions at the SASE Annual Meeting in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in Socio-economic Review</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2020-10-30-ser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 21:20:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2020-10-30-ser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tergen.org/publications/publication_files/2020_ser.pdf&#34;&gt;Article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/ser/advance-article/doi/10.1093/ser/mwaa041/5942748&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Socio-economic Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on the moral economy of economic competition with S. Kohl.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication in the MPIfG Discussion Paper Series</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/news/2020-03-21-mpidp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/news/2020-03-21-mpidp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de/pu/mpifg_dp/2020/dp20-3.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A new discussion paper&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpifg.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MPIfG&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; series on the role of the future in economic action with J. Beckert. A revised version will be published in the &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Economic Sociology for the 21st Century&lt;/em&gt; (Springer Nature, 2020, edited by Andrea Maurer).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of Institutional Theory (University of Cologne)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/19ws_inst/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/19ws_inst/</guid>
      <description>This seminar introduces theories of institutions from across the social sciences, covering classical origins through recent debates about institutional change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on Reagan-era fiscal, trade, and reindustrialization policy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_untergang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_untergang/</guid>
      <description>The paper demonstrates how the Reagan administrations deployed stories of national economic decline to raise popular support for neoliberal reform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on Antitrust in Review of International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_ripe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_ripe/</guid>
      <description>The paper compares competition policy reform in the United States and Europe</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on the dangers of symmetric reasoning</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2019_asymmetry/</guid>
      <description>Social scientists often treat causal relationships as inherently symmetric: if an increase in X leads to an increase in Y, a decline in X will lead to a corresponding decline in Y. This paper challenges this conventional approach and argues that many causal relationships are in fact asymmetric, because their underlying mechanisms work in asymmetric ways. While researchers are aware of this in principle, it is often not reflected in research practice. Therefore, we call on social scientists to pay more attention to the possibility of asymmetric relationships in their theories and their empirical research. They otherwise run the risk of accidentally rejecting sound theories or accepting faulty ones. We develop a typology of different mechanisms generating asymmetry, demonstrate their empirical relevance by replicating empirical studies of electoral dynamics, discuss strategies to deal with asymmetry, and show the relevance of asymmetry for social analysis and political reform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and Society (University of Cologne)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/18ws_inno/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/18ws_inno/</guid>
      <description>This seminar introduces social science perspectives on the origins, forms, and effects of innovation, examining where inventions come from how societies shape and are shaped by technological change.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soziologie multinationaler Unternehmen (University of Duisburg-Essen)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/18ws_mne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/18ws_mne/</guid>
      <description>This seminar examines the historical development, organizational structures, and societal impacts of multinational corporations through a sociological lens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper on innovation policy in a volume on Uncertain Futures</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/papers/2018_aligned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/papers/2018_aligned/</guid>
      <description>The paper compares technology policies for coal liquifaction and solar energy in the 1970s and 1980s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economy and Society II (MPIfG)</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/courses/18ss_ecosoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/courses/18ss_ecosoc/</guid>
      <description>This doctoral seminar focuses on recent debates on the interrelations between economy and society, examining economic action, markets, and modern capitalism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Große Hoffnungen und brüchige Koalitionen: Politik, Industrie und die schwierige Durchsetzung der Photovoltaik</title>
      <link>https://tergen.org/book/book1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tergen.org/book/book1/</guid>
      <description>The book reconstructs the history of policies to support solar photovoltaics across countries.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
